# Marguerite Mei

(647) 997-5519 | mgrtmei@gmail.com | Toronto, ON

## **Core Competency**

Master graduates with background in Finance & Retail, possessed critical thinking and 4 years' analytics experience in Financial Analysis, Corp Accounting, CRM and Marketing. Strong technical thinking and hands on implementation in various data manipulation and data visualization. A true problem solver and team player!

#### Qualification

## ✓ Financial Analyses

Finance & Accounting; SAP Order-to-Cash Cycle; Reconciliation; Budget & Forecasting

### ✓ CRM & Marketing

Customer Behavior & Segmentation; Market Share & Strategic; Campaign Strategy & Analyses; LVMH

#### ✓ Data Analyses

Data Integration, Extraction, Transformation & Load; Data Gap Analysis; Ad hoc queries

#### ✓ Data Visualization

Business Requirement, Power BI, Google Analytics, layout, KPI design, Report Automation

#### **Tech Skills**

- Data: Advanced SQL, Power BI, Google Analytics, MS Access, Enterprise Excel, VBA, Python
- Application & Tools: SAP Sales & Distribution, SPSS, draw.io, Jira, ServiceNow
- Platform: SQL Server, Snowflake, Azure Cloud, Databricks, Data warehouse

#### **Education**

University of Windsor	Sep 2020 - Jun 2022
York University, ON	Sep 2014 – Oct 2019
Seneca College, ON	Sep 2019 – Aug 2020
Google	Aug 2022
	York University, ON Seneca College, ON

# **Work Experience**

# Data Analyst EDPYPF Services Inc.

Jan 2022 - Current

- Collected business requirement via business meeting, data investigation to identify business logic & KPI formula etc
- Monthly Income Statement Reporting Automation using VBA in Access and Excel, which saved 50% time on
- Banking transaction analysis and RFM model on customer migration and segmentation towards launching new credit card
- Designed Power BI dashboard on expense control with YoY and actual vs. budget analysis
- Answered various ad hoc business questions and analyzed industry trends towards Customer Sales database and action on closing gaps with resolving data duplicate and data integrity issues

## **Financial Analyst**

## **Ginis Electronics Technology LLC**

Sep 2017 - Dec 2021

- Automated invoicing process through Excel Marco, VBA to upload invoice data to accounting database.
- Accounts bookkeeping maintenance and data reconciliation for GL, AP, AR in SQL Server 2014
- Worked with bank, internal / external stakeholders on accounting related, like financing, insurance, securities, credit cards, finance income statement and balance sheet.
- Worked with 3rd party company on monthly, quarterly and yearly adjustment, posting, auditing and financial reporting
- Managed 10+ marketing channels across multiple industries seeking for business opportunities in short turnover periods; Arranged project set-up and execution liaising with certain regional demand analyses
- Analyzed and grasped client core demands quickly; Well-prepared with explicit business workflow, objectives, and deliveries

## **Business Analyst**

#### **Axis Communications Inc.**

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- Collaborated with stakeholders from sales and service teams to collect business requirements and lead initiative solutions in data manipulation process; Prepared SQL queries for routine and ad hoc analysis
- Planned event for distributors training campaign, creating contents, and tracking, analyzing subscribers using WeChat
- Developed potential customer through questionnaire and interviews & identified core group through scoring based selection
- Made strategy presentation; praised by C-level clients for research-based insights, establishing new business opportunities

# **Projects Experience**

•	Bell strategies to accelerate prepaid gross subscriber additions	University of Windsor	May 2022
•	Customer based Brand Equity Management Project	University of Windsor	Dec 2021
•	Marty's Department Store – Customer Grouping & Campaign Analyses	York University	Sep 2020